So this is where you were.
こちらにおられましたか
本字幕由✿花語&花丸字幕組✿共同製作
As you predicted, I discovered a secret account.
陛下のおしゃっていた通り 二重帳簿が見つかりました
There are signs that taxes were being illegally diverted.
諸税の管理に不正が行われいた形跡があります
Good work.
ご苦労様です
I have already dismissed the man in charge.
担当者はすでに罷免しました
やはり 腐敗が根深く蔓延っている様です
The corruption runs deep, evidently.
イル王は優しい方だった
King Il was a kind man.
優しさ自体は決して罪ではありません
Kindness is not a crime.
だが それを時として人の持つ弱さや欲を呼び覚ましてしまう
But sometimes, it awakens
weakness and greed in others.
Indeed.
はい
Your Majesty, your late father
declared that a forbidden text.
陛下 それはかつて亡きユホン様が禁書になされた
Yes.
四龍伝説の本です
It's a book on the legend of the four dragons.
子供の頃はよくここに忍び込み
When I was a child, I would often sneak in here
この本を読んでは 胸を躍らせたものです
and find great excitement in reading this book.
だが所詮はお伽話
But it's only a fairy tale.
この高華王国を再び立ち直らせるのは
絵空事の神などではない
Gods of fantasy cannot set
the Kingdom of Kouka aright.
Episode 9:
Shaking Resolve
久しぶりだな
It's been a while.
坊主の薬 待ってたぞ
I've been waiting for your medicine.
お爺さん 米ある
Sir, do you have any rice?
Sure.
それにしても 連れが居る何て
But it's rare to see you traveling with someone.
誰だ そっちのでかい兄ちゃん
Who's the big guy?
Oh...
商売仲間ですよ
I'm a fellow merchant.
ちょいと国境近くまで商売しに
We have business near the border.
姫さん
Princess...
Princess!
何怒ってるんです
What are you so upset about?
袋に詰めて担いだ事
Because I stuffed you in a bag and carried you?
袋に入っているのは衣類だと言って乱暴に扱った事
Because I said there were clothes in the bag and handled you roughly?
袋に入ってるのをいいことに触りまくった事
Because I took advantage of you being in a bag to put my hands all over you?
All of it.
全部
How should I punish you for that?
どうしてくれよ この仕打ち
I was so afraid we'd be discovered that my heart was pounding.
俺はお爺さんにばれないか心臓バクバク
いい あんた達
Listen, you two.
A red-haired princess.
赤い髪のお姫様
BOOM!
野獣の元将軍
A former general and beast.
That's "Thunder Beast."
雷獣だ
BOOM!
And a handsome genius!
天才美少年
BOOM!
POINT!
目立つんだから 大人しくしてよね
We all stand out, so don't draw attention.
POINT!
そしてこの辺は火の部族と王都の近く
Plus, we're near both Fire Tribe territory and the royal capital.
見つかればやばいって分かるよね
You understand it'll be bad
news if they find us, right?
はい
Yes, sir.
しかし 神官といい四龍といい
ややこしい場所に住んでやがる
Still, the priest and the four dragons really live in obnoxious places.
神官様よ 四龍の手掛かりはあるのか
Priest, do you know where
we can find the four dragons?
龍の血を継ぐ者は 今はそれぞれ生活をし
The warriors who inherited the dragons' blood now live and move around separately.
かつ移動しているので
Pinning down their locations is difficult.
場所の特定は難しいのです
What a pain in the ass!
面倒くさっ
But one of them...
ですが一人だけ
Chishin
Saika
Kouka Kingdom
神話の時代より霧深き山の上に住まい ひっそりと
Since the age of myth, a clan has lived atop a mountain shrouded in mist.
Fuuga
Kai Empire
Though they live in secret,
しかし 確実に血を守り続けている一族が居ます
I'm certain they can still be found there, protecting the dragon's blood.
どこの部族にも属さず 他の者を決して受け入れない
They don't belong to any of the tribes, and they never accept outsiders.
Current Location
国境近くだな
That's near the border.
はい
Yes.
You'll have to cut across Fire Tribe territory and pass by its capital,
火の部族と王都の近くを横切るので
so the journey will be dangerous.
危険ですが
王都どころか 戒帝国も近いわ
It isn't just the capital.
It's near the Kai Empire too.
I finally got to travel, so I'm really excited to see this mysterious village.
俺は漸く外に出られたから すげぇ楽しみ 幻の里
国中を旅したら 見聞録を書く
Once I've traversed the kingdom,
I'll record my personal experiences!
どうした 目が赤いぞ
What's wrong? Your eyes are red.
If you miss the priest, you can return to those mountains anytime.
神官様が恋しくなったら
What's your problem? My eyes aren't red!
いつでも戻りな あの山ん中に
うるさい
Shut up!
Hey, Princess!
おい 姫さん
ハク まだけがが治ってないでしょう
Hak, your injuries haven't healed yet.
ずっと私を抱えて旅するの無理よ
You can't carry me for the whole journey.
それに 私は自分の目でこの国をもっとよく見たい
Besides, I want to see this kingdom
with my own eyes.
ま いいでしょう
Okay, fine.
However, don't let your guard down.
ただし くれぐれも気は抜かねぇこと
さっきの話に出たとおり 長閑に見えるけど
As I mentioned earlier,
it may appear peaceful, but...
ね ユン あれはなに
Hey, Yun, what's that?
大きな水車
It's a huge water wheel!
あんなの初めて見た
I've never seen one that big!
ハク これは
Hak, what is this?
Wheat.
麦
They're growing rice over there too.
向こうでは米も作ってるな
この辺は王都のお膝元だからね
This area is under the direct rule of the crown.
あんたが言った城の食糧も
Most of the food you ate in the castle was probably produced here.
主にここで賄われてるんだと思うよ
そうなんだ
Really?
Hey! Look!
ほら 見て
Oh, my.
あら 上手にできたね
Well done.
えらい えらい
That's very good.
大体揃ったね
We have most of the things we need.
But we don't know how long we'll have to stay in the mountains.
けど いつまで山ん中に居なきゃなんないか分かんないし
不安っじゃ不安だな
I'm still a bit nervous.
Yeah.
ハク どうかした
Hak, is something wrong?
なにか 買い忘れた物でも
Did you forget to buy something?
いや
No.
行って来ていいわよ 私 ここでユンと待ってるから
You can go. I'll wait here with Yun.
いいんじゃない
It's probably fine.
見たところ この村やばそな奴等とは変がなさそうだし
From the looks of things,
this village doesn't seem like it's connected to anyone dangerous.
少しでもやばいと思ったら逃げろ
Run at the slightest sign of danger.
その時は村の外の...
We'll meet outside the village.
あの大きな木の所で落ち合うでしょう
By that big tree, right?
We know.
分かってるよ
Yeah.
すぐ戻る
I'll be right back.
大刀と剣は見つかったが
I found my glaive and sword,
but I lost my bow in the mountains.
弓は北山でなくしたきりだったしな
守り刀です
It's a self-defense sword.
小降りですし か弱い女子でも扱いますよ
It's small enough for a frail girl to use.
必要ない
I don't need it.
Protecting her is my job.
守るのは俺の役目だ
Huh?
Really?
じゃ 本当に新しい王様が戴冠なさったのか
A new king really was crowned, then?
Yeah. According to the rumors,
he's quite young and handsome.
なんでも噂じゃ 随分若くて男前らしいが
But he's Yu-hon's son, right?
けど ユホン様のご子息だろう
He must be a terrifying man.
そっか
I see.
じゃ ムンドクはあの後スウォンが王座に就くのを承認したのね
Then Mun-deok must have given
his approval to Su-won's coronation.
よかった これで風の部族に危害が及ぶことがない
I'm relieved. Now the Wind Tribe will be safe.
どうしたの
What's wrong?
Are you all right?
大丈夫
Yeah.
スウォンが あの城の...
Su-won is the ruler of the castle.
父上亡き後の王座に
He has taken my late father's throne.
Are you listening?
ね 聞いてる
Miss?
お嬢さん
Would you like another drink?
もう一杯如何かで
ありがとう
Thank you.
でも 結構です
But I'm fine.
Hey...
ちょっ 待ってよ
Wait!
お爺さん お代
Sir, here's your payment.
ま まいど
Th-Thank you.
急にどうしたのさ
What's gotten into you?
You should try not to act suspicious.
無駄に怪しまれる様な行動は控えないと
Hurry! This way.
早く こっち
まずったな
This isn't good.
多分王都にでも行っていて 留守だったんだ
They probably weren't here before
because they were visiting the capital.
Hey!
どうも
Hello.
When did you return from Kuuto?
何時空都からお戻りで
Just now.
つい今さっきだ
Really?
そうでしたぁ
都は華やかだったぞ
The capital was gorgeous.
Yeah?
It was as lively as a banquet.
まるで宴のように賑わっていて
Everywhere I looked, I saw food and drink I'd never seen before.
初めて見る食べ物や酒が至る所にあった
That's incredible.
そいつはすごい
Yeah.
You should come with me sometime.
まるで宴のように賑わっていて
It was as lively as a banquet.
初めて見る食べ物や酒が至る所にあった
Everywhere I looked, I saw food and drink I'd never seen before.
That's incredible.
そいつはすごい
姫さん 静かに
Be quiet, Princess.
Let's go. We shouldn't linger.
行くぞ 長いは無用だ
I'm sorry. I was careless.
悪い 俺の気の緩みだ
やはりお前等をお二人にすべきじゃなかった
I shouldn't have left you two alone.
いや 俺が...
No, I...
ごめんなさい
I'm sorry.
I heard that because a new king has been crowned,
taxes will be decreased.
王様が変わって少しは税が軽くなるって話だぞ
期待すんなよ
Don't expect too much.
No matter who rules, they'll never understand our hardship and pain.
誰が王権だろうか 俺達の苦労や傷みを分かってくれる訳がねぇ
Climbing is rough, but I'm glad we don't have to worry about being watched.
登りはきついけど 人目を気にしなくてもいいのは助かるな
Don't lower your guard.
油断するな
火の部族の兵士が巡回していないとは限らねぇ
There's no guarantee that Fire Tribe soldiers aren't patrolling the area.
私 覚えなきゃ 剣術
I need to learn swordsmanship.
Hak, you said you would teach me.
ハク 教えてくれるって言ったよね
言ってませんが
No, I didn't.
みちすがらでもいいから 教えて
You can teach me while we travel.
I need to be able to repel attackers.
誰が襲ってきても撃退できるように
姫さん
Princess...
あんたに人が殺せるのか
could you kill someone?
撃退と言っても 都合よく敵が逃げるわけじゃない
You may try to repel enemies,
but they won't just run away.
You must kill or permanently incapacitate them.
殺す もしくは再起不能にする
あんたにできるか
Can you do that?
北山で追い詰められたあの時も
When we were cornered in the mountains,
私 剣を持ってたのに 全然使えなかった
I had a sword, but I couldn't use it.
敵わなくても 殺せなくても
Even if I'm outclassed, even if I can't kill,
I want to be able, at least,
to create opportunities for escape.
自分やハクが逃げる隙を作るくらいはやりたい
Self-defense swordsmanship.
護身用の剣術
教えてくれる
Will you teach me?
分かりました
Very well.
弓？
A bow?
俺が前線で戦う
I'll fight on the front lines.
姫さんは身を隠して敵を狙う
You'll fire at our opponents while staying hidden.
Okay.
はい
ね 剣も頂戴
Give me a sword too.
今は弓しか教えません
For now, I'll only teach you the bow.
姫様
Princess, King Il never let you handle weapons.
イル陛下は決して姫に武器を触らせなかった
俺は今 陛下の命に背きます
Now I am disobeying the orders of my king.
何故陛下が武器を嫌ったのか よく考えてみてください
You should consider why the king hated weapons.
But how can you train with a bow
while hiking through mountains?
でもさ 山登りながら 弓の訓練とかってどうするの
そうだな
Well...
旅の途中でなけりゃ 一日二百本以上射させるんだが
If we weren't traveling, I'd make her shoot two hundred arrows a day.
Two hundred?!
二百
とりあえず 鳥や兎を弓で仕留めるかな
But for now, I guess you can practice shooting birds or rabbits.
I approve. If you shoot something,
we'll eat it for dinner.
それ賛成 とったら夕食に困らないし
よろしく お姫様
I'm counting on you, Princess.
What...
What?!
One Hour Later
Wobble
Flap Flap
Flap Fl ap
Hak, I can't hit anything.
ハク 当たらない
どうすればいいの
What am I supposed to do?
こんな感じ
That.
How did you do that?
それどうやったの
狙う
I aimed.
分からない
I don't get it.
何が
Don't get what?
天才は出来ない人の気持ちが分からない
Prodigies don't understand how the incompetent feel.
Prodigies don't understand
how the incompetent feel.
ハクは先生にはなれないわね
You could never be a teacher, Hak.
待って待って
Hold it.
いいですか
Listen up.
Basically, you lack strength.
根本的にあんたには力が足りない
振るえずに弦を引く力をつけて 後は...
You must build the strength to draw the bow without shaking, and then...
体で覚える
Learn by doing.
A master archer can strike
a target with his eyes closed.
本当の弓の名士は 目を瞑ってでも的を当てるらしいから
Don't be deceived by what you see.
目に映るものに惑わされないように
とりあえず 今は真っ直ぐ矢を飛ばす事を考えなさいな
For now, focus on shooting straight.
What's that sound?
She's practicing archery this late at night?
弓の練習...こんな時間に
今朝は鶏肉の炊き込みご飯だ
This morning, we're having poultry and rice.
美味しそう
That looks delicious!
ユンって本当になんでもできるのね
You really can do anything.
Well, I am a genius.
ま 天才だからね
様になってきたんじゃない
Your shooting posture is getting better.
Really? Can you shoot a bow?
本当 ユンは弓できる
できなくはないけど
Well, I'm not incapable,
but it's best not to take up
weapons half-heartedly.
生半可な気持ちなら 武器を持たない方がいいよ
Huh?
人を殺すか殺さないかの話
I'm talking about whether you can kill someone.
護身用って言ってるけど
You say it's for self-defense,
but do you really think powerless people like us are shown pity on the battlefield?
俺らの様な力のない人間が戦場に放り込まれて
情けなんてかけられると思う
For us to survive,
俺らが生き残るには
容赦なく急所を狙う一撃必殺の技か
we need to learn merciless techniques that strike at vital points,
ここ 頭脳戦しかないって事
or use this and rely on mental battles.
手加減したりなんて器用な真似は
The Thunder Beast can afford to hold back
because of how strong he is.
あの雷獣さんだから出来る事なんだよ
可愛い
It's cute.
Even if it were human, I'd have
to shoot it on the battlefield.
あの子が人であったとしても
戦場ならば矢を当てなければ...
Drawing a bow means taking and losing lives.
弓を引くという事は
命を奪い 奪われる事
父上が嫌った痛み
My father hated pain.
But, Father, to survive I have to take lives.
でも父上
奪わなければ 私は今 生きてゆけません
You almost had it.
惜しかったですね
無駄にけがさせた
I injured it needlessly.
反って残酷だね
That's just cruel.
迷いがあるからでしょう
Because you hesitated.
ユン 先に行け
Yun, go on ahead.
いいけど 早く来てよね
Sure, but you'd better come soon.
もうすぐイクスの言ってた場所だから
We're nearly at the place Ik-su mentioned.
あ すぐに追いつく
Okay. We'll be right there.
さて どこまで上達したか 先生が見てあげましょう
Now, then. Show your teacher how much progress you've made.
はい
Okay!
まずはこの木
First, try to hit this tree.
おめでとうございます さすがです
Congratulations! I knew you could do it.
とりあえず当たってます
You hit the tree.
なぜかしら 忌々しいわ
For some reason, I resent you right now.
But it was a compliment...
後は そうだな
What else? Well...
But it was a compliment...
明明是稱讚她
俺 狙ってください
Aim for me.
無理
I can't!
It's all right. I'll dodge it.
大丈夫 避けますから
You'll practice hitting a moving target.
動いてるものに当てる練習
いや 人に当てる練習だな
No, you'll practice shooting a person.
I'll move around. Try to shoot me.
適当に動きますから 射ってください
当たっても知らないから
Don't blame me if I hit you!
Hak! Don't move around so much!
もうハクっだら ちょこまかしない
まだまだ 当たる気はしませんね
You aren't even close to hitting me.
まだまだ殺気が足りない
You lack the intent to kill.
さ 殺気何て ある訳ないでしょう
Th-The intent to kill?
Of course I lack that.
じゃ 追手だと思えばいい
Then imagine I'm one of your pursuers.
あんたが殺したいと思う相手を想像しろ
Envision the men who want to kill you.
No one like that exists!
そんな相手 私にはいない
Really? Then...
そうか じゃ
俺をスウォンだよ思って撃て
imagine I'm Su-won and shoot.
お前のそう言う所 嫌いよ
I hate this side of you.
それでも
But...
to protect you, I'm willing to take up a weapon,
お前を守る為なら
誰かを犠牲にしてでも 武器を手にしたいと望むの
even if it means sacrificing someone!
ハク
Hak...
守るとか そう言う事言うな
Don't say you'll protect me.
どうして
Why not?
欲が出る
It stirs my desire.
とにかく 守るのは俺の仕事です
In any case, it's my job to protect you.
俺を道具だと思えって言ったでしょう
I told you to think of me as a tool.
You don't have to worry about your tools.
道具の心配はしなくていいんです
大分視界が悪くなってたな
It's gotten harder to see.
ユン どこまで行ったのかしら
How far did Yun go?
霧深き幻の里
A mysterious village, shrouded in mist.
この辺だと思うが 里なんてどこに
It should be around here somewhere, but where is the village?
ハク 大変
Hak, there's trouble!
何も見えん
I can't see anything.
Where are you?
どこです
Here! Come quickly!
ここ 早く来て
ハク これ ユンの荷物よね
Hak, these are Yun's belongings.
ユン どこ
Yun! Where are you?
返事して
Answer me!
Leave! Leave!
去れ 去れ
Leave this land immediately.
この地より 即刻立ち去れ
Who's there?
だれ
If you intrude any further,
the gods will punish you.
これ以上踏み込めば 天罰が下されるであろう
Your gods must be quite magnificent to punish people while hiding in the mist!
霧に隠れて天罰だ さぞご立派な神なんでしょうね
主ら何者
Who are you?
一振りで我らの霧を晴らすとは
You cleared our mist with a single swing.
Are you from the dragon's village?
あんたら 龍の里の門か
我々一族を知っているようだな
You're familiar with our tribe.
All the more reason we cannot let you leave alive.
ならば益々生きて帰すわけにはいかぬ
Is the boy one of your friends too?!
先程の小僧もお前らの仲間か
ユンを連れて行ったのは貴方達
Did you take Yun?
ユンはどうしたの
What did you do to Yun?
The boy...
あの小僧は
You!
そなた
Red hair...
赤い髪
赤い髪だ
Red hair.
まさか
Could it be?
But she's a young girl.
しかし少女だ
何処より参られたか 赤い髪の少女よ
Where did you come from, red-haired girl?
風の地
From the Wind Tribe's lands.
神官様のお導きにより四龍の戦士を訪ねてきた
A priest instructed me to seek
out the four dragon warriors.
Do you possess the blood of a dragon?
あなたは四龍の血を持つ人
神官様だと
A priest?
No. We are guardians of the White Dragon.
いいえ 我々は白き龍の守り人
ご案内しましょう 白龍の里へ
We will show you the way to the village of the White Dragon.
Do you see
wakaru kai
What I'm trying so hard to convey through my work?
muriyari demo sakuhin de tsutaetokitai koto wo
It's always been this way, hasn't it?
mukashi to kawaranai daro
The same obscure lyrics and background
yomizurai kashi mo haikei mo
I've always talked ideals
sasaeru da to ga erasou ni sa
Like supporting others
nando mo nando mo itta kedo
私は古より受け継がれし 龍の血を引く者
I hope you don't realize too early
kotoba no karusa omoishiru no wa
お待ちしておりました 我が主よ
次回 暁のヨナ 第十話
How irresponsible I was being with my words
hayasuginai you ni
待望
There's a reason why the snow is so cold
yuki ga tsumetai wake nante
Since my hands are warmer than others'
boku no te ga hito yori atsui kara
When I hold your hand
kimi no sono te wo tsunaida toki
I'll be able to bring out the warmth in you
atatakai wo hikidasu tame
Next Time
I have inherited the blood of the dragon, passed down from ancient times.
I have been waiting for you, my master.
Next time, Akatsuki no Yona, episode 10:
Episode 10:
Anticipation
Anticipation.